THOMAS LIN

11 Rose St, Antigonish, B2G 1C5 Nova Scotia, Canada Phone: +15812004150

Email: thomaslin920@gmail.com

Software Engineer with over 5+ years of experience developing mobile applications and web products. Specialized in writing Front-End applications with scalable, component, architecture. Focus on high code quality providing modern and best solutions based on best practices, customer's goals, and expectations.

EXPERIENCE

2020.8 – 2022.5
SOFTWARE ENGINEER, KONEKTA

Job Type: Permanent, Full time, Remote

Location: Sydney, Australia

- Rebuilt the frontend written in Aurelia framework in React.js/Typescript
- Used Material UI to build a mobile-responsive interface and split redux/redux-saga to handle state management
- Applied DDD approach and implemented CQRS and Event Store on the backend side
- Setup swagger to auto-generate API interface in TS types for use on the frontend side
- Implemented PDF generation functionality using Wkhtmltopdf library
- Integrated Stripe/PayPal payment for both one-time and monthly subscription payments
- Wrote Jest unit tests and Cypress e2e tests and set up the Azure pipeline to run both tests before deployment

2018.5 - 2020.7

FRONTEND ENGINEER, VISIONE

Job Type: Permanent, Full time, Remote.

Location: Fairfield, NJ, US

- Converted expo app into React Native one
- Integrated OCR technology into the app for scanning business cards with Google Vision API
- Used i18n to support multi-languages
- Identified entities within documents with google language API
- Implemented several image animations, rotating, Cropping, drawing
- Integrated with Salesforce, Google API, Microsoft Dynamics, Outlook

- Worked on app security in real-time, improved top minification of the code, encrypted database
- Created IOS and Android apps and published them to Appstore and Google Play Store.

2016.11 – 2017.10
SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, YINGDONG SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY
DEVELOPMENT CO, LTD

Job Type: Permanent, Full time, on-site.

Location: Beijing, China

- Developed hybrid mobile automotive field app from scratch using React Native to provide car service (washing, repairing)
- Integrated Alipay and WeChat pay payment into the app for achieving group purchases, card vouchers, and other activities
- Implemented pixel-perfect app based on the design provided
- Created various components including tables and cards field up with professional and practical information of automotive field fetched from Django back-end
- Helped dashboard application development and hosting it on Aliyun web service
- Developed a web portal where the employee can submit their project ideas and request resources needed for the project.

EDUCATION

SEP 2012 - JUN 2016

BEIJING UNIVERSITY OF POSTS AND TELECOMMUNICATOINS

Bachelor's degree of Computer science and technology

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, C

• Front-End: React.JS, React Native, Next.JS, Vue.JS

Back-End: Node.JS

• Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

API: REST, GraphQL (Apollo, Prisma)

• Server: Firebase, AWS, Heroku

• Unit Testing: Cypress. Jest

• Other: Twilio API, Payment Integration